<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nathan Harrington - patents</title><link href="nathanharrington.info/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="nathanharrington.info/feeds/patents.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>nathanharrington.info/</id><updated>2014-12-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Vector Space Lightweight Directory Access Protocol Data Search</title><link href="nathanharrington.info/posts/vector-space-lightweight-directory-access-protocol-data-search.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-12-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><author><name>Nathan Harrington</name></author><id>tag:,2014-12-23:nathanharrington.info/posts/vector-space-lightweight-directory-access-protocol-data-search.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A computer-implemented method, apparatus, and computer program product
for performing a search for data. In one embodiment, the process
    converts each character of the search query into a phonetic variant
    to form an inflected search query. The process then identifies a set
    of inflected data fields of a vector space library satisfying the
    inflected search query. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Beyond Field-of-View Tracked Object Positional Indicators</title><link href="nathanharrington.info/posts/beyond-field-of-view-tracked-object-positional-indicators.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><author><name>Nathan Harrington</name></author><id>tag:,2013-11-19:nathanharrington.info/posts/beyond-field-of-view-tracked-object-positional-indicators.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A system and method for implementing beyond field-of-view tracked object
positional indicators for television event directors and camera
operators. The present invention includes a camera having a
field-of-view. The camera tracks an off-screen object. A coordinate
manager blends an on-screen indication of distance that the object is
away from said field-of-view. The camera is positioned to avoid the
object in the field-of-view. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Automatic announcer voice removal from a sporting event</title><link href="nathanharrington.info/posts/automatic-announcer-voice-removal-from-a-sporting-event.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><author><name>Nathan Harrington</name></author><id>tag:,2013-08-20:nathanharrington.info/posts/automatic-announcer-voice-removal-from-a-sporting-event.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A sound processing circuit divides an audio input signal of a televised
sporting event into multiple audio segments. The audio input signal
includes crowd noise and announcer commentary. If an audio segment does
not exceed a pre-defined amplitude threshold, a voice removal utility
adds the audio segment to a recent crowd noise library and stores the
segment in an output buffer. If the amplitude of a segment exceeds the
threshold, the utility adds the segment to a recent announcer voice
library. The sound processing circuit generates an attenuated version of
the segment and blends the attenuated version with one or more mixed
segments from the recent crowd noise library. The voice removal utility
stores the attenuated and blended segment in the output buffer and
outputs one or more audio segments from the buffer in a chronological
order. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Visualization interface of continuous waveform multi-speaker identification</title><link href="nathanharrington.info/posts/visualization-interface-of-continuous-waveform-multi-speaker-identification.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><author><name>Nathan Harrington</name></author><id>tag:,2013-01-01:nathanharrington.info/posts/visualization-interface-of-continuous-waveform-multi-speaker-identification.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The programming instructions are operable to create a voiceprint from
the current waveform if the current waveform is of a human voice.
Furthermore, the programming instructions are operable to determine one
of whether a match exists between the voiceprint and one library
waveform of one or more library waveforms, whether a correlation exists
between the voiceprint and a number of library waveforms of the one or
more library waveforms and whether the voiceprint is unique.
Additionally, the programming instructions are operable to transcribe
the current waveform into text and provide a match indication display
(MID) indicating an association between the current waveform and the one
or more library waveforms based on the determining.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Reducing multipath signal degradation effects in a wireless transmission system</title><link href="nathanharrington.info/posts/reducing-multipath-signal-degradation-effects-in-a-wireless-transmission-system.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><author><name>Nathan Harrington</name></author><id>tag:,2012-06-26:nathanharrington.info/posts/reducing-multipath-signal-degradation-effects-in-a-wireless-transmission-system.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A transmitter transmits a signal to a receiver along a transmission
path. The respective positions of the transmitter and the receiver are
determined, and notice is received that a moving vehicle is proximate to
the transmission path. Responsive to such notice, the moving vehicle
position is determined, and such position is used with the transmitter
and receiver positions to determine whether the moving vehicle is
located between the transmitter and receiver positions. The calculated
time delay is then used to provide a corrective signal component, which
is employed to reduce degradation of the first component. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Upper troposphere and lower stratosphere wind direction, speed and turbidity monitoring using digital imaging and motion tracking</title><link href="nathanharrington.info/posts/upper-troposphere-and-lower-stratosphere-wind-direction-speed-and-turbidity-monitoring-using-digital-imaging-and-motion-tracking.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><author><name>Nathan Harrington</name></author><id>tag:,2012-05-08:nathanharrington.info/posts/upper-troposphere-and-lower-stratosphere-wind-direction-speed-and-turbidity-monitoring-using-digital-imaging-and-motion-tracking.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The visible sky is monitored by a set of cameras for contrails produced
by a high-altitude aircraft. In response to identifying a contrail, the
contrail is tracked across the field of view of the camera. Contrail
data generated when the contrail is identified and during the tracking
of the contrail is stored. The contrail data describes characteristics
of the contrail including the spread of the contrail and the movement of
the contrail across the field of view of the camera. Coordinates of the
high-altitude aircraft are determined and compared with the contrail
data to identify wind conditions. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Hybrid ultrasonic and radio frequency identification system and method</title><link href="nathanharrington.info/posts/hybrid-ultrasonic-and-radio-frequency-identification-system-and-method.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-03-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><author><name>Nathan Harrington</name></author><id>tag:,2012-03-20:nathanharrington.info/posts/hybrid-ultrasonic-and-radio-frequency-identification-system-and-method.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A radio frequency identification system and method includes a tag reader
and radio frequency identification tag. The tag reader includes an
ultrasonic transducer capable of transmitting tones at selected
ultrasonic frequencies and a radio transmitter capable of transmitting
signals at selected radio frequencies. The tag reader includes a radio
receiver capable of receiving signals at selected radio frequencies. The
tag reader determines if a received radio frequency signal is modulated
at a selected ultrasonic frequency. The radio frequency identification
tag includes an array of combination resonator/reflectors. Each
combination resonator/reflector of the array includes an ultrasonic
resonator coupled to a radio reflector. Each resonator/reflector of the
array is tuned to a unique pair of selected ultrasonic frequencies and
selected radio frequencies. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Autonomously Configuring Information Systems to Support</title><link href="nathanharrington.info/posts/autonomously-configuring-information-systems-to-support.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><author><name>Nathan Harrington</name></author><id>tag:,2011-05-24:nathanharrington.info/posts/autonomously-configuring-information-systems-to-support.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Mission SoulPad may autonomously detect and configure components of
the information system (e.g., displays, sensors, emitters, transceivers)
to support the defined objectives of the Mission SoulPad. The Mission
SoulPad may also identify malfunctioning components of the information
system needing repair or replacement. Entire sensor and information
display suites may be transitioned simply by moving the Mission SoulPad
between available information systems. This ensures that mission
critical information is consistently available regardless of the type of
system the Mission SoulPad is connected to. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Automatically generating precipitation proximity notifications</title><link href="nathanharrington.info/posts/automatically-generating-precipitation-proximity-notifications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-05-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><author><name>Nathan Harrington</name></author><id>tag:,2011-05-07:nathanharrington.info/posts/automatically-generating-precipitation-proximity-notifications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A method and system for automatically generating a notification of a
status of precipitation being received by a user-defined detection zone
within a geographic area. An image of the geographic area is received.
The image includes pixels associated with the detection zone. Each pixel
is associated with a sub-area of the detection zone. Characteristics
(e.g., colors) of the pixels are obtained. The characteristics indicate
intensities of precipitation being received by sub-areas of the
detection zone.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Method and system for vehicle mounted infrared wavelength information displays for traffic camera viewers</title><link href="nathanharrington.info/posts/method-and-system-for-vehicle-mounted-infrared-wavelength-information-displays-for-traffic-camera-viewers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><author><name>Nathan Harrington</name></author><id>tag:,2011-01-18:nathanharrington.info/posts/method-and-system-for-vehicle-mounted-infrared-wavelength-information-displays-for-traffic-camera-viewers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Systems and methods for vehicle mounted infrared wavelength information
displays for traffic camera viewers are disclosed. A method includes
obtaining vehicle positioning data associated with at least one vehicle
and, based upon the vehicle positioning data, selectively emitting
infrared wavelength light from a set of a plurality of light emitting
diodes (LEDs) arranged on exterior surfaces of the at least one vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Protecting electronic devices from percussive impacts</title><link href="nathanharrington.info/posts/protecting-electronic-devices-from-percussive-impacts.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><author><name>Nathan Harrington</name></author><id>tag:,2011-01-04:nathanharrington.info/posts/protecting-electronic-devices-from-percussive-impacts.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A system and method detects low grade physical motions of an electronic
device, such as a laptop computer, and takes protective measures if the
physical motions match a pre-specified physical motion pattern. The
pre-specified physical motion pattern may have been selected as a
pattern which, if left alone, could cause cumulative damage to the
electronic device. Alternatively, the pre-specified motion pattern may
have been selected as a pattern which tended to indicate that more
aggressive and abrupt movements would be forthcoming. The system and
method further detects sustained motion (such as in a laptop bag) such
that the laptop may shut-off so that the laptop does not overheat or get
damaged. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Method and system for improving driver safety and situational awareness</title><link href="nathanharrington.info/posts/method-and-system-for-improving-driver-safety-and-situational-awareness.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><author><name>Nathan Harrington</name></author><id>tag:,2010-04-06:nathanharrington.info/posts/method-and-system-for-improving-driver-safety-and-situational-awareness.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A method for enhancing driver safety through body position monitoring
with remote sensors, and furnishing feedback in response to vehicle
motion, driver activities, and external driving conditions. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Automotive collision detection through passive radio analysis</title><link href="nathanharrington.info/posts/automotive-collision-detection-through-passive-radio-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-06-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><author><name>Nathan Harrington</name></author><id>tag:,2009-06-09:nathanharrington.info/posts/automotive-collision-detection-through-passive-radio-analysis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The present invention discloses a vehicular collision alert system which
receives signals from devices commonly associated with vehicular use.
The direction of the received signals is determined, and a heading of
the signal source is also determined and compared with the present
location and heading of the vehicle If the comparison indicates a
sufficient chance of a collision, and alert is generated to notify the
driver of the vehicle of the potential collision. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>